mclasshome.com 2019-06-22

# Customer privacy policy - Amplify

## Introduction

Amplify Education, Inc. (“Amplify” or “we”) is reimagining the way teachers teach and students learn in K-12 education. Our products are leading the way in data-driven instruction, breaking new ground in mobile learning and setting the standard for next-generation digital curriculum and assessment. A central part of our work is helping educators improve classroom education by using data in a way that is safe, secure, and effective.

In the course of providing our educational products and services, we take numerous measures to maintain the security and confidentiality of personal information[1](https://www.amplify.com/customer-privacy#footnote-1) collected or stored by Amplify on behalf of our customers, School Districts[2](https://www.amplify.com/customer-privacy#footnote-2) and State Educational Agencies[3](https://www.amplify.com/customer-privacy#footnote-3). In doing so, we enable our customers to control use, access, sharing and retention of personal information in compliance with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”) and other applicable privacy laws and regulations (“Applicable Privacy Laws”).

## Scope of the policy

This Amplify Customer Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) applies to our School District and State Educational Agency customers who have contracted with Amplify to purchase our products and services, as well as the authorized users of such products and services. There may be different contractual terms and privacy policies in place with some of our customers. Such other terms and policies may supersede this Policy for information collected or released under those terms. If you have any questions as to what legal agreement or privacy policy controls the collection and use of your information, please contact us using the contact information below.

This Policy describes:

  * what information is collected on behalf of our School District and State Educational Agency customers via our products and services;
  * how Amplify uses that information;
  * with whom Amplify shares that information; and
  * what steps Amplify takes to safeguard this information and ensure that our School District and State Educational Agency customers remain in control of their data at all times.

## Types of information collected

There are two types of information that Amplify collects and stores on behalf of our School District and SEA customers: (i) information provided by the customer to support the use of our products and (ii) information provided by students, teachers and other school personnel in the course of using our products.

### Information provided by our customers

Most of Amplify’s educational products require some basic information about who is in a classroom and who teaches the class. For example, when a teacher logs into an Amplify application that provides student assessment results, a list of students associated with that teacher may be displayed in the application. Amplify’s software looks this information up in a database that contains roster information (e.g. name, grade level, school ID numbers) that the School District supplied to Amplify.

Our customers may also choose to provide additional student demographic data and other school records (e.g. grades, attendance, assessment results) to Amplify for tailoring individual learning programs or enabling additional reporting capabilities through Amplify products. For example, a School District customer may wish to analyze student literacy assessment results based on English Language Learner status in order better differentiate classroom instruction.

### Information collected through our products

Our customers use Amplify products and services to improve educational outcomes, in part by using student data to enable greater individualization of classroom instruction. Students and teachers use our products to engage in a variety of educational experiences, many of which entail inputting personal information. This information falls into several different categories listed below along with examples for each category:

  * **Student responses and activities**. Students may provide answers to quizzes, tests, essay prompts and other assessments, enter homework assignments, engage in interactive activities, or answer direct teacher questions as part of the digital learning experience.
  * **Teacher comments, activities, and other input**. Teachers may create lesson plans, enter notes on instructional strategies, performance and needs, or provide other education-related content or observations using Amplify products. Certain Amplify products also receive information about teacher activities within a classroom to enable assignment of quizzes or polling students.
  * **Photos, videos, and audio files**. Tablets and other devices have image, video and audio recording capabilities that can be used by students and educators for learning inside and outside the classroom.
  * **Online forums and other community features**. Some of our products and services may enable students and teachers to share their information on message boards, online forums, chat, profile pages and blogs, or other community services to which they are able to post information and materials.
  * **Device performance and status**. Device diagnostic information, such as battery level and installed applications may be collected to support the proper functioning of the device.
  * **Geolocation**. Tablets and other mobile devices may come equipped with geolocation capabilities that can be used to support features in certain apps or locate missing or stolen devices. Such capabilities may be controlled and limited by the settings selected by the School District or SEA customer or the device end user.
  * **Device and Browser Data**. Characteristics of device and browser configurations and persistent identifiers, such as IP addresses and device identifiers, are collected along with associated usage data. Some of our products use “cookies,” Web beacons, HTML5 local storage and other similar technologies to collect and store such data. This data is collected to support the security mechanisms of the product and our internal operations, as well as to enable analysis of aggregate usage trends and improve the learning experience. In addition, some products also provide content filtering and may analyze website traffic to filter for inappropriate content.
  * **System usage**. Amplify may collect system usage information, such as the number of requests a device makes, in order to ensure proper system capacity for all users.

## Use of information

Amplify uses information collected and stored on behalf of our customers to support the learning experience and to ensure secure and effective operation of our products. In particular, Amplify may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * to provide our educational products and services and to support our School District and SEA customers’ and their end users’ activities;
  * to respond to the inquiries and fulfill the requests of our School District and SEA customers and their end users;
  * to send administrative information to our School District and SEA customers and their end users;
  * in the case of customer personnel (e.g., teachers and administrators), to send product information to such personnel;
  * to personalize end users’ experience with our products and services;
  * to improve the effectiveness of our products and support our product development;
  * to report on aggregate trends and usage statistics;
  * to enforce product access and security controls; and
  * to conduct system audits and improve protections against the misuse of our products.

## Disclosure of information

We will only share personal information stored on behalf of our customers with third parties if authorized by the relevant School District or SEA customer and in the following situations, to the extent we believe in good faith it is necessary or appropriate and permitted by law:

  * to comply with the law, respond to requests in legal or government enforcement proceedings (such as complying with a subpoena), protect our rights in a legal dispute, or seek assistance of law enforcement in the event of a threat to our rights, security or property or that of our affiliates, customers, end users or others;
  * in the event Amplify or its assets are acquired or transferred to another party, including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings, provided that such disclosure will be subject to this Policy and any successor to the relevant business will be required to comply with this Policy with respect to information collected under this Policy;
  * to work with third parties who conduct studies or assist us in providing and improving our products and services, such as platform, infrastructure, software and other types of service providers, agents, partners and researchers. We contractually bind such parties to protect personal information by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Amplify; and
  * except as restricted by the contract with our School District or SEA customers, we may also share personal information collected or stored in Amplify systems with Amplify’s affiliated education companies, provided that such disclosure is solely for the purposes described in Section 4 and at all times is subject to this Policy.

## Third party services

Some of our products and services may be used in conjunction with or enable access to third party services and products, such as those from operating system providers, social media platforms, wireless service providers, device manufacturers, and other application or service providers.

This Policy does not address, and Amplify is not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of such third parties, including any third party operating any service to which an Amplify product or service links. School Districts and SEA customers should carefully consider which third party applications to include among the products and services they provide to students and vet the privacy and data security standards of those providers.

## Security

Amplify uses industry standard administrative, technical, operational and physical measures to safeguard personal information in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. Please see [amplify.com/security](https://www.amplify.com/security) for a detailed description of Amplify’s security program.

In the event Amplify discovers or is notified of an unauthorized disclosure of personal information within our possession or control, we will, as required by applicable federal and state laws, investigate, take steps to mitigate the potential impact, provide notice of the breach to applicable agencies, including School District and SEA Customers.

## Review and correction

FERPA requires schools to provide parents with access to their children’s education records, and parents may request that the school correct records that they believe to be inaccurate or misleading. If you are a parent or guardian and would like to review, correct or update your child’s personal information stored in our product or service, contact your School District. Amplify will work with your School District to enable your access to and, if applicable, correction of your child’s education records.

If you have any questions about whom to contact or other questions about your child’s personal information, you may contact us using the information provided below.

## Data retention

We will retain personal information collected from our School District and SEA customers for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy and our agreement with that School District or SEA customer. Specifically, at the direction of our customers, Amplify will return or destroy personal information stored by Amplify in accordance with applicable law and customer requirements.

## Updates to this policy

We may change this Policy in the future. For example, we may update it to comply with new laws or regulations, to conform to industry best practices, or to reflect changes in our product offerings. Such changes to the Policy will become effective when we post the revised Policy on our website. However, in the event there are material changes in our practices with respect to use and disclosure of personal information, we will notify our School District and SEA customers affected by the changes, and the changes will become effective when the School District or SEA customer accepts the new policy.

## Contact us

If you have questions about this Policy, please contact us at:

Email: [privacy@amplify.com](mailto:privacy@amplify.com)

Mail: Amplify, 55 Washington St., Ste 900, Brooklyn, NY, 11201 Attn: General Counsel

## Footnotes

  1. “Personal information” means any student information defined as personally identifiable information under FERPA or as personal information under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). This includes the student’s name, address, email, social security number and other information that, alone or in combination, would allow a reasonable person in the school community to identify the student with reasonable certainty.
  2. “School District” means a local educational agency, school network, independent school or other school system.
  3. “State Educational Agency” or “SEA” means the educational agency primarily responsible for the supervision of public elementary and secondary schools in any of the 50 states, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia or other territories and possessions of the United States, as well as a national or regional ministry or department of education in other countries, as applicable.
